

Gustavo Rayos













575-520-5199

gustavorayos @outlook.com San Francisco Bay Area gustavorayos.com

@gustavorayos

@gustavorayos

Summary

Dedicated Computer Systems Engineer with knowledge of creating elegant solutions in a timely manner. Experienced in System Administration, Security, Networks, and Development. Performs system configuration, workstation patching, vulnerability management, and network analysis. Provides user support to technical issues while staying friendly and professional. Leads software, security, group policy, and vulnerability management initiatives from a technical aspect. Has developed in PowerShell, Bash, C, Java, CSS, and JavaScript. Enthusiastic about learning new skills. Received Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science from New Mexico State University. Active DoD Secret Security Clearance.

Skills

HARD SKILLS

- SCCM
- WDS & MDT
- SCAP
- STIGViewer
- Active Directory
- Group Policy
- Linux (RHEL)
- Citrix
- VMWare
- Hyper-V

- TenableSplunk
- DHCP
- DNS
- Mac OS
- Git

LANGUAGES

- PowerShell
- Bash
- DOS/Windows
- C
- C++
- Java
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- CSS
- HTML

Work Experience

SYSTEMS ENGINEER (DOD SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE)

Raytheon Missile Systems | Tucson, AZ | March 2019 - Current

- Developed software package which automates our standard operating system (OS) configuration on Test Equipment (TE).
- Deployed a Windows Deployment Server (WDS) and Microsoft Deployment Toolkit (MDT) server and was responsible for task sequence configuration and client system deployment.
- Responsible for Windows and RHEL STIG configuration.
- Works with Cyber Security attending meetings for TE software and hardware configuration.
- Attends Sigma Six discussions providing useful feedback as a member of a project team.
- Responsible for Test Equipment (TE) computer systems working as a member of a system administration team.
- Participates in system design, security solutions, system imaging, data recovery, hardware diagnostics, and unique problem solutions in multiple heterogeneous network environments.
- Assists with managing user accounts, network access, generation and maintenance of web page content, infrastructure, database support, and system backups.
- Provides solutions to a variety of technical problems of moderate scope and complexity primarily with internal company contacts.
- Infrequent inter-organizational and outside customer contacts on routine matters.
- Responsible for system documentation.
- Works under general directions, and follows established procedures to determine and develop approaches to solutions.
- Responsible for program success.
- DoD Secret Security Clearance.

CNS Pantex | Amarillo, TX | December 2015 - March 2019

- Attended weekly Vulnerability Assessment Management meetings and help responsibility for technical patching on Pantex systems. Security patching included Microsoft and 3rd party applications.
- Calculated Site Performance Review (SPR) monthly metrics, and reviewed system compliance on the Pantex network. Average monthly system compliance on the Pantex network was 99% compliant.
- Reviewed and approved non-standard security exceptions for individual users and systems.
- Maintained server accessibility and health by running daily checks on multiple Microsoft and Linux servers.
- Developed security protocols and procedures using various tools including PowerShell scripts, SCCM,
 Group Policy, Active Directory, Tenable, Splunk, Citrix, and more.
- Created and configured standalone system media for government issued laptops which included Cisco AnyConnect VPN software.
- Acted as a direct contact for PeopleSoft, Java, Acrobat, Reader, Flash Player, and deployments.
- Acted as a direct contact for any VPN related issues.
- DoE Q Top Secret Security Clearance

WEB DEVELOPER

Rayos Design | Amarillo, TX | March 2018 - February 2019

- Developed website code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React languages.
- Configured Apache2, MySQL, PHP, and domain name services on web server.
- Maintained an organized workflow by using various tools including source control (Git), Visual Studio Code, and other tools.
- Tested and maintained client websites to ensure compatibility with various browsers, operating
 systems, devices, and screen sizes. Google Chrome developer tools, various devices, and various
 browsers were used to test website function and performance.
- Hosted websites from personal servers and developed PHP code to provide instructions for user input on websites.
- Designed websites to be user friendly while keeping performance in mind.
- Maintained active conversations with clients to ensure their needs are met.
- Researched industry trends to provide the most modern and top-quality designs.

HIGH-PERFORMANCE COMPUTING RESEARCHER

Los Alamos National Laboratory | Los Alamos, NM | May 2015 - August 2015

- Researched object storage software called Ceph.
- Contributed work to a team of 3 computer science interns.
- Conducted read and write tests on a computer cluster of 11 nodes. Increased performance of default configuration of Ceph object storage software by 11%.
- Built a Linux computer cluster of 11 nodes and configured DNS, DHCP, NTP, NFS, HTTP, Authentication and Authorization, Users and Groups, LDAP, and Kerberos.
- Presented finding to Los Alamos National Laboratory computer scientists.

COMPUTER SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

Dona Ana Community College | Las Cruces, NM | August 2014 - January 2015

- Provided general field support for faculty, students and other employees.
- Assisted users by using remote access software to troubleshoot issues they were experiencing.
- Answered computer related questions from users of university computers.
- Organized software and hardware closets.

Education

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

New Mexico State University | Las Cruces, NM | January 2014 - December 2015

Followed my passion for computers and programming and excelled in Java and C programming courses. Completed network security and architecture courses. Researched high performance computer software and

completed my senior project on Ceph Object Storage software. Also minored in Software Development and Algorithms Theory. Graduated with a 3.5 GPA.

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BIOLOGY

New Mexico State University | Las Cruces, NM | August 2007 - May 2013

Completed studies in Biology and continued on to work in an environmental laboratory. Minored in Biochemistry. Graduated with a 3.5 GPA.